Guide to the James Crumley Additions
The Wittliff Collections
James Crumley Additions
circa 1962-2014
The Wittliff Collections https://www.thewittliffcollections.txstate.edu
Crumley, James, 1939-2008
UPWC.14140
18 boxes Plus oversize
Additions documenting the writing career of James Crumley with added notes and content by screenwriter and first wife, Martha Elizabeth.
Conditions Governing Access
Collection is open for research.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of James Crumley, 2014.
Scope and Contents
Additions documenting the writing career of James Crumley with added notes and content by screenwriter and first wife, Martha Elizabeth.
Separated Materials
"Il Caso Sbagliato/The Wrong Case" Italian translation, [2 copies], 1991
"Il Caso Sbagliato/The Wrong Case" Italian translation, 1993
"Il Confine Dell'Inganno/Bordersnakes" Italian translation, [2 copies]
"La Contrée Finale/The Final Country" French translation, [2 copies]
"La Danse de l'Ours/Dancing Bear" French translation, [2 copies]
"Feil Sak/The Wrong Case" Norwegian translation, [2 copies]
"The Final Country" paperback, [2 copies], 2002
"The Final Country" paperback, [2 copies], 2003
"The Final Country", hardback large print, [2 copies]
"The Mexican Tree Duck", [2 copies]
"The Mysterious Press Anniversary Anthology"
"One to Count Cadence", [2 copies]
"Putes/Whores" French translation, [2 copies]
"La Terra Della Menzogna/The Final Country" Italian translation, [2 copies]
"Uno Que Marque El Paso/One to Count Cadence" Spanish translation, [2 copies]
Audiobooks on cassette tape:
"Bordersnakes", [2 copies]
"Dancing Bear", [2 copies]
"The Final Country"
"The Last Good Kiss", [2 copies]
"The Mexican Tree Duck", [2 copies]
"One to Count Cadence", [2 copies]
"The Putt at the End of the World"
"The Wrong Case", [2 copies]
Index Terms
Subjects
Screenwriters -- United States; Screenplays; American poetry -- Texas
Places
Texas -- Fiction
Subjects (Persons)
Crumley, James, 1939-2008
- 2014-140
  Scope and Contents
  Personal papers of author James Crumley. These items were collected from his home and reflect Crumley's professional writing career and personal life. This collection includes multiple drafts of Crumley's screenplays and novels, international translations, and publicity; some writings by other authors; drawings and work by Crumley's first wife, Martha Elizabeth; correspondence; a sampling of documents that reflect his medical and financial history; reviews; publicity; photographs; office files; contracts; books; and personal artifacts.
  - "The Right Madness" partial draft, undated (Box 1884, Folder 1)
  - "The Right Madness" draft with corrections by Martha Elizabeth, undated (Box 1884, Folder 2-3)
  - "The Right Madness" corrected draft, undated (Box 1884, Folder 4-5)
  - "The Right Madness" draft, undated (Box 1884, Folder 6-7)
  - "The Right Madness" corrected draft, undated (Box 1884, Folder 8)
  - "The Right Madness" incomplete draft, undated (Box 1884, Folder 9-10)
  - "The Right Madness" draft fragments, undated (Box 1884, Folder 11)
  - "The Right Madness" corrected draft, undated (Box 1884, Folder 12)
    - "The Right Madness" interior design proofs, 2004 (Box 1884, Folder 13)
    - "The Right Madness" page proofs, 2004 (Box 1884, Folder 14-15)
    - "The Last Good Kiss" screenplay: first draft, January 21, 1979 (Box 1884, Folder 16-17)
    - "The Last Good Kiss" screenplay: miscellaneous pages, undated (Box 1884, Folder 18)
    - "The Last Good Kiss" notes by Martha Elizabeth, undated (Box 1885, Folder 1)
    - "The Last Good Kiss" screenplay: printed on long sheets of paper, undated (Box 1885, Folder 2)
    - "The Last Good Kiss" incomplete screenplay; notes by Martha Elizabeth, undated (Box 1885, Folder 3)
    - "The Last Good Kiss" annotated screenplay, undated (Box 1885, Folder 4)
  - "The Right Madness" interior design proofs, 2004 (Box 1884, Box 13)
  - "The Right Madness" page proofs, 2004 (Box 1884, Box 14-15)
  - "The Last Good Kiss" screenplay: first draft, January 21, 1979 (Box 1884, Box 16-17)
  - "The Last Good Kiss" screenplay: miscellaneous pages, undated (Box 1884, Box 18)
  - "The Last Good Kiss" corrected screenplay, undated (Box 1885, Folder 5-7)
  - "The Last Good Kiss" screenplay, undated (Box 1885, Folder 8-9)
  - "The Last Good Kiss" screenplay by Walter Hill, undated (Box 1885, Folder 10)
  - "The Last Good Kiss" screenplay by Michael Jenning: first draft, undated (Box 1885, Folder 11)
  - "The Last Good Kiss" screenplay by Willie Goldman, September 27, 2003 (Box 1885, Folder 12)
  - "The Last Good Kiss" screenplay by Willie Goldman, November 14, 2003 (Box 1885, Folder 13)
  - "The Last Good Kiss" screenplay by Willie Goldman; includes letter and film project "game plan", June 11, 2008 (Box 1885, Folder 14)
  - "The Last Good Kiss" screenplay by Willie Goldman, July 30, 2009 (Box 1885, Folder 15)
  - "The Last Good Kiss" screenplay by Martha Elizabeth, March 2012 (Box 1885, Folder 16)
  - "The Last Good Kiss" screenplay by Martha Elizabeth: first draft, April 2012 (Box 1885, Folder 17)
  - "The Last Good Kiss" screenplay by Martha Elizabeth, July 2012 (Box 1885, Folder 18)
  - Two audiocassettes: James Crumley reading "The Last Good Kiss" and an interview with Crumley, undated (Box 1885, Folder 19)
  - "Dancing Bear" corrected draft, [working title: "Save the Last Dance for the Bear"], undated (Box 1885, Folder 20-22)
  - "Dancing Bear" draft fragment, undated (Box 1886, Folder 1)
  - "Dancing Bear" corrected draft, undated (Box 1886, Folder 2-3)
  - "Dancing Bear" incomplete draft, (note: mildew damage), undated (Box 1886, Folder 4)
  - "Dancing Bear" screenplay by Crumley and Tim Hunter: first draft, August 23, 1985 (Box 1886, Folder 5-8)
  - "Dancing Bear" screenplay by Crumley and Tim Hunter: revised, undated (Box 1886, Folder 9-10)
  - "Dancing Bear" screenplay: multiple drafts, undated (Box 1886, Folder 11)
  - "Dancing Bear" screenplay by Crumley: first draft, February 2, 1992 (Box 1886, Folder 12)
  - "Dancing Bear" screenplay by Crumley: second draft, November 13, 19922 (Box 1886, Folder 13)
  - "Dancing Bear" screenplay by Michael Koepf and Edward Taylor: first draft, June 14, 1996 (Box 1886, Folder 14)
  - "Dancing Bear" screenplay by Crumley, Tim Hunter, and Robert Towne: merged draft, July 19, 2000 (Box 1886, Folder 15)
  - "Dancing Bear" screenplay by Crumley, John Fasano, and Tim Hunter, July 26, 2001 (Box 1886, Folder 16)
  - Dancing Bear" screenplay by Crumley and Gwenyth Mapes: first act before Towne's notes, undated (Box 1886, Folder 17)
  - "Dancing Bear" screenplay: multiple partial drafts, undated (Box 1886, Folder 18)
  - "Dancing Bear" screenplay, undated (Box 1886, Folder 19)
  - "Dancing Bear" screenplay: first draft, polish, undated (Box 1886, Folder 20)
  - "Dancing Bear" screenplay by Crumley: third draft, undated (Box 1887, Folder 1)
  - "Dancing Bear" incomplete screenplay, undated (Box 1887, Folder 2)
  - "Dancing Bear" corrected screenplay, undated (Box 1887, Folder 3-4)
  - "Dancing Bear" screenplay by Crumley, undated (Box 1887, Folder 5)
  - "Dancing Bear" screenplay: third draft; includes "Story Meeting Notes" and 'Short Step Outline" and "Story Proposals", undated (Box 1887, Folder 6-7)
  - "Dancing Bear" screenplay, page 119, undated (Box 1887, Folder 8)
  - "Bordersnakes" first draft, February 14, 1996 (Box 1887, Folder 9-12)
  - "Bordersnakes" final draft, April 30, 1996 (Box 1887, Folder 13-15)
  - "Bordersnakes: Version #1, the original manuscript typeset printout, w/my corrections, recommendations, & codicils, etc.", undated (Box 1887, Folder 16)
  - "Bordersnakes" box lid for previous draft "Version #1…", undated (Box 1887, Folder 17)
  - "Bordersnakes: Version #2, Maura's corrections of my correction of the original typeset printout" (note: description written on a Kinko's box), undated (Box 1888, Folder 1)
  - "Bordersnakes: Version #3 The Cleanest Copy" (note: description written on a Kinko's box), undated (Box 1888, Folder 2)
  - "Bordersnakes" partial manuscript, notes, editorial notes; and miscellaneous pages from "Dancing Bear [?]", undated (Box 1888, Folder 3)
  - "Bordersnakes" manuscript, October 17, 1997 (Box 1888, Folder 4-5)
  - "Bordersnakes: Author's First Laser Proof", undated (Box 1888, Folder 6-7)
  - "The Mexican Tree Duck" second draft, February 1993 (Box 1888, Folder 8-9)
  - "The Mexican Tree Duck" draft, undated (Box 1888, Folder 10-11)
  - "The Mexican Tree Duck" edited manuscript; includes editorial notes, undated (Box 1888, Folder 12-13)
  - "The Mexican Tree Duck" original manuscript submitted to publisher (1 of 2), undated (Box 1888, Folder 14)
  - "The Mexican Tree Duck" original manuscript submitted to publisher (2 of 2), undated (Box 1889, Folder 1)
  - "The Mexican Tree Duck" proof "Author's Set", undated (Box 1889, Folder 2)
  - "The Mexican Tree Duck" [?] screenplay fragment, undated (Box 1889, Folder 3)
  - "The Big Nowhere" screenplay: first draft, November 16, 1990 (Box 1889, Folder 4)
  - "The Big Nowhere" screenplay: second draft, September-October 1990 (Box 1889, Folder 5)
  - "The Big Nowhere" screenplay: second draft, February 1991 (Box 1889, Folder 6)
  - "The Big Nowhere" screenplay: fourth draft, August 15, 1991 (Box 1889, Folder 7-8)
  - "The Big Nowhere" screenplay draft, 1993 (Box 1889, Folder 9)
  - "The Big Nowhere" screenplay draft, undated (Box 1889, Folder 10-11)
  - "Blood Borne" screenplay: second draft revisions, April 11, 1995 (Box 1889, Folder 12)
  - "Bloodwork" screenplay: first draft, July 12, 1995 (Box 1889, Folder 13-14)
  - "Bloodwork" screenplay: second draft revised, February 1997 (Box 1889, Folder 15)
  - "Bloodwork" screenplay draft, undated (Box 1889, Folder 16)
  - "The Pigeon Shoot" screenplay: first draft, December 13, 1983 (Box 1889, Folder 17-18)
  - "The Pigeon Shoot" screenplay proof, undated (Box 1889, Folder 19-20)
  - "The Far Side of Jericho" screenplay by Crumley and Rob Sullivan, October 4, 2004 (Box 1890, Folder 1)
  - "The Far Side of Jericho" screenplay: white production draft, April 1, 2005 (Box 1890, Folder 2)
  - "The Far Side of Jericho" screenplay: multiple drafts, undated (Box 1890, Folder 3)
  - "The Far Side of Jericho" screenplay: incomplete draft, undated (Box 1890, Folder 4)
  - "Judge Dredd" screenplay: first rough draft, December 12, 1987 (Box 1890, Folder 5)
  - "Judge Dredd" screenplay: first draft, undated (Box 1890, Folder 6)
  - "Judge Dredd" screenplay draft, undated (Box 1890, Folder 7)
  - "Last Chance" screenplay: first draft, October 1987 (Box 1890, Folder 8)
  - "Last Chance" screenplay draft, undated (Box 1890, Folder 9)
  - "Last Chance" screenplay: draft fragments, undated (Box 1890, Folder 10)
  - "Last Chance" screenplay draft, undated (Box 1890, Folder 11-12)
  - "Last Chance" screenplay: partial draft, undated (Box 1890, Folder 13)
  - "Last Chance" screenplay draft; includes Martha Elizabeth's notes, October 6, 2008 (Box 1890, Folder 14)
  - "Last Chance" screenplay draft, October 25, 2008 (Box 1890, Folder 15)
  - "Last Chance" screenplay draft, undated (Box 1890, Folder 16)
  - "Last Chance" program for a performance at the "Montana Repertory Theatre", undated (Box 1890, Folder 17)
  - "Hostages" short story, undated (Box 1890, Folder 18)
  - "Hostages" notes from Martha Elizabeth's adaptation, undated (Box 1890, Folder 19)
  - "Hostages" screenplay by Martha Elizabeth: multiple drafts, October 2011, undated (Box 1890, Folder 20)
  - "Hostages" screenplay by Martha Elizabeth: multiple drafts, November 2012 (Box 1890, Folder 21)
  - "The Mexican Pig Bandit" draft, undated (Box 1890, Folder 22)
  - "The Mexican Pig Bandit" proof, February 1998 (Box 1890, Folder 23)
  - "The Mexican Pig Bandit" draft; includes layout, October 29, 1998, undated (Box 1890, Folder 24)
  - "Butch Cassidy and the Sundance Kid", screenplay by William Goldman with Crumley's notes: final draft, July 15, 1968 (Box 1890, Folder 25)
  - "Deception Pass: A Scenario for an Original Screenplay" [two copies], undated (Box 1890, Folder 26)
  - "Movie Narration", undated (Box 1890, Folder 27)
  - "Untitled" screenplay by James Crumley: first draft, October 1987 (Box 1890, Folder 28)
  - "Untitled" screenplay by Crumley and Gwenyth Mapes: first draft, August 1988 (Box 1890, Folder 29)
  - "Untitled" screenplay by Crumley and Gwenyth Mapes: first draft, August 1988 (Box 1891, Folder 1)
  - "Streets of El Paso" treatment, undated (Box 1891, Folder 2)
  - "The Tunnels of Cu-Chi", screenplay: revised first draft, undated (Box 1891, Folder 3)
  - "The Tunnels of Cu-Chi" screenplay draft, undated (Box 1891, Folder 4)
  - "Badwater Canyon" screenplay: second draft, 1998 (Box 1891, Folder 5-6)
  - "The Final Country" draft, undated (Box 1891, Folder 8)
  - "The Final Country" draft; includes editorial notes, undated (Box 1891, Folder 9-10)
  - "The Final Country" draft, undated (Box 1891, Folder 11-12)
  - "The Final Country" multiple incomplete drafts, undated (Box 1891, Folder 13)
  - "The Final Country" incomplete draft, undated (Box 1891, Folder 14-15)
  - "The Final Country" manuscript given to publisher, undated (Box 1891, Folder 16-17)
  - "Microwave Park" screenplay; includes screen credits correspondence (1 of 2), undated (Box 1891, Folder 18)
  - "Microwave Park" screenplay; includes screen credits correspondence (2 of 2), undated (Box 1892, Folder 1)
  - "Microwave Park" screenplay by Crumley [?], title page by Eugene Hess, undated (Box 1892, Folder 2)
  - "Microwave Park" screenplay by Eugene Hess, undated (Box 1892, Folder 3)
  - "Microwave Park" screenplay draft, undated (Box 1892, Folder 4)
  - "Microwave Park" printout of internet article: "De Niro, 50 Cent Star in Katrina Thriller", undated (Box 1892, Folder 5)
  - "The Snow White Laughing Girl & Seven Sullen Dwarves" short story draft, undated (Box 1892, Folder 6)
  - "Coming Around the Mountain" short story draft, undated (Box 1892, Folder 7)
  - "Coming Around the Mountain" short story draft with edits by Martha Elizabeth, undated (Box 1892, Folder 8)
  - "Hot Springs" short story: multiple drafts and first pass proof, August 24, 1995 (Box 1892, Folder 9)
  - "A Message from the Corner of Space and Time" short story draft, undated (Box 1892, Folder 10)
  - Notes on "William Kittredge", undated (Box 1892, Folder 11)
  - "Geezer Wisdom" short story draft, undated (Box 1892, Folder 12)
  - "Getting Out" short story: galley proof, undated (Box 1892, Folder 13)
  - "Road Trip-for the Buddha and the Moon" poem: multiple drafts, undated (Box 1892, Folder 14)
  - "Introduction for Falling Angel" layout, 2006 (Box 1892, Folder 15)
  - "Degrees of Gray at Northside" poem draft, undated (Box 1892, Folder 16)
  - "Where do the Women Go When the Women Go Away?" short story draft, undated (Box 1892, Folder 17)
  - "The Smoke" short story draft with edits by Martha Elizabeth, undated (Box 1892, Folder 18)
  - "Untitled" screenplay draft, undated (Box 1892, Folder 19)
  - "Wingshot" draft by Max Crawford, undated (Box 1892, Folder 20)
  - "Wamba" draft by Max Crawford, undated (Box 1892, Folder 21)
  - "The Red & The White" uncorrected proof by Max Crawford, undated (Box 1892, Folder 22)
  - "The Red & The White: Volume II" uncorrected proof by Max Crawford, undated (Box 1892, Folder 23)
  - "High School Harry & Co" uncorrected draft by Max Crawford, undated (Box 1892, Folder 24-25)
  - "Eastertown: Volume I" uncorrected proof by Max Crawford, undated (Box 1892, Folder 26)
  - College course packet that includes readings of Crumley's work, undated (Box 1892, Folder 28)
  - Photocopies of French articles on Crumley, undated (Box 1892, Folder 29)
  - MA thesis on Crumley: "Between Mythologies and Traditions: Liminality in the Detective Novels of James Crumley", 1992 (Box 1892, Folder 30)
  - Book about the Irish heritage of the Crumley name, undated (Box 1892, Folder 31)
  - "An Evening with the Doctor", a graphic novel by Charles Fischer, undated (Box 1892, Folder 32)
  - French book of photographs that includes photo of Crumley, undated (Box 1893, Folder 1)
  - French dissertation on Crumley, "Decadence and Disillusionment in James Crumley's Novels", 1999 (Box 1893, Folder 2)
  - Article: "Sex, Drugs, and Divided Identities: The Detective Fiction of James Crumley" by John Scaggs, undated (Box 1893, Folder 3)
  - Office files- "Offer in Compromise" [financial], 2002 (Box 1893, Folder 4)
  - Office files- "Final Country" contract, undated (Box 1893, Folder 5)
  - Office files- "The Missoula Artists' Shop", October 1999 (Box 1893, Folder 6)
  - Office files- "Montana Festival of the Book Missoula", September 6-8th, 2001 (Box 1893, Folder 7)
  - Office files- "Get Lit! 2000 EWU Press", October 6-8th, 2000 (Box 1893, Folder 8)
  - Office files- "Professional Activities/Correspondence & Info Current Year", 2000 (Box 1893, Folder 9)
  - Office files- "Mortgage Statements/Coupons-Current Year", 2000 (Box 1893, Folder 10)
  - Office files-"Etonnants Voyageurs St. Malo-Previous", 1999 (Box 1893, Folder 11)
  - Office files-"Hellgate Productions Correspondence Previous Year"; "Hellgate Productions Misc. Old", 1999 (Box 1893, Folder 12)
  - Office files- "Writer's Guild" correspondence and financial, undated (Box 1893, Folder 13)
  - Office files- "Financial" documents, undated (Box 1893, Folder 14)
  - Office files- "Jeffrey Light L.A. Lawyer", undated (Box 1893, Folder 15)
  - Office files- "Frequent Flyer-Old", undated (Box 1893, Folder 16)
  - Office files- "Writer's Guild Health Fund", undated (Box 1893, Folder 17)
  - Office files- "Child Support/Divorce-Old", undated (Box 1893, Folder 18)
  - Office files- "Royalty Statements-Old", undated (Box 1893, Folder 19)
  - Office files- "Child Support", undated (Box 1893, Folder 20)
  - Office files- "Royalty Statements", undated (Box 1893, Folder 21)
  - Office files- "William Morris", undated (Box 1893, Folder 22)
  - Office files- Contracts, undated (Box 1893, Folder 23)
  - Office files- Page proofs for: "In the Heart of the Cup" published in "The Putt at the End of the World", undated (Box 1893, Folder 24)
  - Office files- "Old Travel Stuff", undated (Box 1893, Folder 25)
  - Office files- "Old Contracts", 1994-1998 (Box 1893, Folder 26)
  - Office files- "Old Contracts", 1989-1993 (Box 1893, Folder 27)
  - "W" newspaper with quote by Crumley, 1983 (Box 1893, Folder 28)
  - "Royalty Statements", undated (Box 1893, Folder 29)
  - "Celebration Festival of the Book", undated (Box 1893, Folder 30)
  - "Right Madness Press Clippings", undated (Box 1893, Folder 31)
  - French publications, undated (Box 1893, Folder 32)
  - "Second Lieutenants of Literature" by Thomas Zigal: proof, undated (Box 1894, Folder 1)
  - "Nick Carter" magazine, (note: torn cover and edges), April 1934 (Box 1894, Folder 2)
  - Reviews/press clippings, undated (Box 1894, Folder 3)
  - List of James Crumley uncollected short pieces, undated (Box 1894, Folder 4)
  - "Clippings-Both", (note: includes announcement of James Crumley & Martha Elizabeth reading), undated (Box 1894, Folder 5)
  - Japanese book that includes a catalog of titles-including Crumley, undated (Box 1894, Folder 6)
  - "Journeés Nationales du Livre et du Vin" catalog, 1997 (Box 1894, Folder 7)
  - "American Bookseller" magazine, August 1988 (Box 1894, Folder 8)
  - "James Crumley" article by Robert E. Burkholder, undated (Box 1894, Folder 9)
  - Rick DeMarinis's- French translation of book and associated PR material, undated (Box 1894, Folder 10)
  - Office papers- Montana softball team, cards, and notes, undated (Box 1894, Folder 11)
  - "Art Info.", undated (Box 1894, Folder 12)
  - "2007 File"- Magazine articles; USA Today reviews (including Crumley's review of "Lonesome Dove"); correspondence (Box 1894, Folder 13)
  - Drawings from publisher sent to Crumley to show cover art, undated (Box 1894, Folder 14)
  - Crumley & Elizabeth Bizlog- record of daily activities, 2003 (Box 1894, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence; reviews; PR; and clippings, undated (Box 1894, Folder 16-18)
  - Correspondence; contracts; financial documents, undated (Box 1894, Folder 19)
  - Catalogs featuring Crumley's books, undated (Box 1894, Folder 20)
  - Catalog "Noir in Festival 1997" featuring Crumley book (Box 1894, Folder 21)
  - Newspaper clippings, undated (Box 1895, Folder 1-3)
  - Contracts; receipts, undated (Box 1895, Folder 4)
  - Writing expenses/travel receipts, undated (Box 1895, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence; including letter to Gary Cartwright, June 7, 2006, undated (Box 1895, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence related to "Damn Near Dead", 2006 (Box 1895, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, 2005, undated (Box 1895, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence-IRS and medical bills, undated (Box 1895, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence-IRS; medical; letters related to writing, undated (Box 1895, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence, 1980-1999 (Box 1895, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence-Divorce documents; IRS; medical; postcards, undated (Box 1895, Folder 12)
  - Court documents related to custody and divorce, undated (Box 1895, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence-William Morris Agency, 1986 (Box 1895, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence, undated (Box 1895, Folder 15)
  - Get Well cards for Crumley (1 of 2), 2002 (Box 1895, Folder 16)
  - Get Well cards for Crumley (2 of 2), 2002 (Box 1896, Folder 1)
  - Journal for Scotland trip, circa 1970-1989 (Box 1896, Folder 2)
  - Notebook from Crumley's memorial service, October 12, 2008 (Box 1896, Folder 3)
  - Crumley's vita, undated (Box 1896, Folder 4)
  - Two photographs, undated (Box 1896, Folder 5)
  - Presents from Martha to Crumley: poetry and artwork, undated (Box 1896, Folder 6)
  - Book jackets: "The Mexican Tree Duck" and "One to Count Cadence", undated (Box 1896, Folder 7)
  - Book jackets: "The Final Country" and "The Mexican Tree Duck", undated (Box 1896, Folder 8)
  - "Club Med" book: "Cadavres Exquis in Cancun" includes Crumley, undated (Box 1896, Folder 9)
  - Short stories & partial drafts: "South of the Muddy Fork"; "Lovely Wounds"; "Hookers' Luck"; and "Untitled", undated (Box 1896, Folder 10)
  - "Presidential Memorial Veteran Certificate", undated (Box 1896, Folder 11)
  - Crumley's obituaries and messages received, undated (Box 1896, Folder 12)
  - Memorial card with photos, undated (Box 1896, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence re: "The Flight of the Butterflies", undated (Box 1896, Folder 14)
  - Photographs, undated (Box 1896, Folder 15)
  - "Swissair Gazette" proof, undated (Box 1896, Folder 16)
  - Publicity cards for Crumley novels, undated (Box 1896, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence; various publicity material, undated (Box 1896, Folder 18)
  - French correspondence and publications, undated (Box 1896, Folder 19)
  - "Neon" magazine with contribution by Crumley: multiple copies, 2006 (Box 1896, Folder 20)
  - "Final Country-Press Clippings", undated (Box 1896, Folder 21-22)
  - "Final Country-Postcard, undated (Box 1896, Folder 23)
  - Correspondence, undated (Box 1896, Folder 24)
  - French newspaper and international packet, undated (Box 1896, Folder 25)
  - Miniature address book, undated (Box 1897, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence and contracts, undated (Box 1897, Folder 2)
  - "Mystery Train" press packet, undated (Box 1897, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence and contracts, undated (Box 1897, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence and miscellaneous office papers, undated (Box 1897, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence; office papers; PR for "One to Count Cadence", undated (Box 1897, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence-includes letters from Maggie, Crumley's second wife, undated (Box 1897, Folder 7-8)
  - Certificates-military, marriage, birth, undated (Box 1897, Folder 9)
  - Diploma-Iowa, MFA, 1966 (Box 1897, Folder 10)
  - Diploma-"Texas College of Arts & Industries", BA, 1965 (Box 1897, Folder 11)
  - Diploma-Mathis High School, 1957 (Box 1897, Folder 12)
  - Elementary school certificate, undated (Box 1897, Folder 13)